Laajavuorentie 9 b 25 40740 Jyväskylä +358415072725 tsoikkeli@gmail.com http://t-m.fi @tusoikke



Tuomas-Matti Soikkeli

Summary

I am an information technology enthusiast. I'm an avid programmer with interests in user experience, cloud computing and web development. My most prominent skillset revolves around JavaEE and web applications. In my spare time I like to spend time with my two lovely children. I also enjoy music and gaming in their diverse forms.

Professional Experience Software Developer, Descom Oy

Spring 2014

Hardcore enterprise software development in logistics domain using Agile, Scrum, JavaEE, Hibernate, Knockout.js, jQuery, REST, SOAP, Git, Maven, Vagrant, Docker, Microservices, Netflix OSS, Spring Boot, Jenkins and Jira.

Software Developer, Architect, Consultant, Droidoro Oü

2013 -

Mobile software design and implementation including low-level communications protocol implementation. Backend service development with Spring stack.

Teaching Assistant, University of Jyväskylä

Spring semester 2014

Teaching assistant in Basic Game Programming course using C#/XNA

Software Developer, kateiskuitti.fi

January 2014

Designed and programmed receipt printer desktop software using Java with Swing.

Software Specialist, City of Jyväskylä

September 2012 - September 2013

Superuser, trainer and application specialist in Effica (healthcare and patient records management software) by Tieto corporation.

Backend Programmer, University of Jyväskylä

Winter semester 2012

Backend programmer in a student project between Tieto corporation and University of Jyväskylä. I designed and programmed RESTful web service using Java, MongoDB, JAX-RS technology stack.

Teaching Assistant, University of Jyväskylä

Spring semester 2012

Teaching assistant in Programming 1 course. I taught basic programming skills with Java language throughout the course.

Web Developer, Freelancer

2003

Crafted a static website from graphical layouts using HTML and CSS.

EDUCATION

University of Jyväskylä, Information Systems Science

2009-

Bachelor of Science (Economics) Student

Thesis: NoSQL-databases: comparsion to relational databases and classification by data model.

College of Jyväskylä

2006-2009

Practical Nurse

Rudolf Steiner School of Jyväskylä

1994 - 2004

Undergraduate

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Supervisor for Mentally Handicapped, City of Jyväskylä	2007 – 2013
Psychriatric Nurse, Central Finland Health Care District	2010-2011
Shift Manager, Hesburger Oy	2006-2009
Ranger, Conscription (6 months)	2004-2005

Language Finnish: Native language

Proficiency English: Excellent written and comprehended, good oral

Swedish: Basics German: Basics

CERTIFICATES, LICENSES Drivers licence (ABC) First aid licence (2008) Hygiene licence (2004)